Contact

miguel.c.amado@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/miguel-amado-7171755 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Team Management
Project Management
Architecture

Languages

Engli

French (Full Professional)

Miguel Amado

Partner, Consulting at EY

Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal

Summary

Over 25 years of Global experience in Business performance improvement projects involving big transformations in the private and public sector. I am currently dedicated and passionate for digital transformation in organizations, specially in the public sector and Health and life sciences.

Specialties: Digital transformation, Business architecture, PMO, TMO, IT solutions design, Business transformation, people development, team management, project and program management.

Main Sectors: Government and Public Sector; Health and Life Sciences; Retail and Consumer Products.

Experience

EY

15 years 4 months

Partner

July 2014 - Present (10 years 10 months)

Lisbon

Senior Manager

January 2010 - June 2014 (4 years 6 months)

ROFF

Free Lancer

May 2009 - December 2009 (8 months)

BI component on a retail project

Wayfield

Project Director

July 2008 - May 2009 (11 months)

Responsible for the ERP Project

PT SI

Project manager

February 2005 - June 2008 (3 years 5 months)

Managing projectos in the area of Business Inteligence and CRM, mainly with SAP technology

Unilever

Manager

July 2002 - February 2005 (2 years 8 months)

Responsible for special projects in the Order to cash area (SD and LE) and Go-live manager for the roll-outs of European project ECLIPSE.

Part of the Unilever European Young managers with High potencial.

Capgemini

3 years 11 months

Senior Consultant

September 1998 - July 2002 (3 years 11 months)

Started with E&Y as a junior consultant in the SD/MM area for SAP implementations. Became senior consultant in the same area and added SAP CRM and BW to my CV with some training and projects on those 2 solutions.

Senior Consultant 2000 - 2002 (2 years)

Education

Universidade Católica Portuguesa

Business administration · (1991 - 1998)

Instituto Superior Técnico

Post graduated, POSI - Information systems and technology · (2006 - 2007)